udayton.edu 2016-04-12

# Privacy Policy : University of Dayton, Ohio

## Privacy Policy

This policy was created in order to demonstrate the University of Dayton's commitment to privacy and security, as well as to disclose all procedures related to information gathering and dissemination practices. The following discloses information gathering and dissemination practices for select University of Dayton (UD) websites and associated media and services at the University of Dayton. 

For the purposes of this policy, "us", "we", and "our" refers to the University of Dayton and/or UD employees, both as representing the aforementioned web sites covered by this policy; "you" and "your" refers to you as an individual user of such a website.

## Information UD Gathers and Uses

The majority of public information and services on our websites are offered without the gathering of any personally identifiable information from you.

### Information Provided by You Directly to Us

The gathering of personally identifiable information by our websites is required in certain instances. Those instances may include: logging in and/or customizing a site; purchasing products or services; submitting certain online forms for registration, application, or related activities; or contacting us. You will always be aware when we are gathering your personally identifiable information, as you will be entering and/or submitting that information through an online form and/or similar method. Your personally identifiable information may be used by us to provide information and services.

### Information Provided by You to Divisions of UD

In certain instances, personally identifiable information that you provide and/or have provided to certain divisions of UD, for other activities such as applying for admission, registering for courses, etc., may be used by us to better serve you. In all such instances, personally identifiable information is provided and used within appropriate guidelines, and only to the extent to which it is necessary in your ability to use our websites, and/or for us to provide you with information and services. Your personally identifiable information may be used by us to provide information and services.

### Information Gathered from You Passively by Us

UD websites passively gather information about you. Such passive gathering may not be readily noticeable to you, and may include, but not be limited to: IP Address, domain from which you access the Internet, individual pages accessed within a UD website, access and session times, environmental variables such as web browser, platform, and operating system, the URL from which you came, the URL you visit when leaving. This information is gathered and analyzed to enhance our websites, detect problems, determine trends, maintain security, and overall, to assist us in improving the offering of information and services. This information is generally non-personally identifiable, however, may be combined with personally identifiable information to better provide information and services.

### Cookies

To enhance the information and services provided, many of our websites utilize "cookies." Cookies are small text files we place on your computer, associated to your computer's Web browser. These cookies do not and will never contain personally identifiable information; however, information stored in these cookies may be linked to personally identifiable information gathered in a manner as previously indicated.

As you browse University of Dayton sites, advertising cookies may be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. Our display advertising partner, AdRoll, then enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with University of Dayton. The techniques our partners employ do not collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address or telephone number. You can visit this [page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) to opt out of AdRoll and their partners’ targeted advertising.

### Information UD Disseminates to Others

Information disseminated by us to any UD division, office and/or official. In certain instances, in order to provide information and services, we may disseminate both non-personally and personally identifiable information to any UD division, office, and/or official. Such instances in which we disseminate information may not be readily noticeable to you, and may include, but not be limited to: taking online exams; registering for courses; purchasing products or services; submitting certain online forms for registration, application, or related activities; or electing interests or preferences. In all such instances, personally identifiable information is disseminated and used within appropriate guidelines, and only to the extent to which it is necessary in our ability to provide information and services, and/or the ability of any UD division, office, and/or official to do the same.

### Information Disseminated by Us to Strategic Partners and Others

In certain instances, we may disseminate to strategic partners and others outside UD both non-personally and personally identifiable information for research, presentation, and/or to provide information and services. In such instances information will be provided only to the extent to which it is necessary in our ability to provide information and services, and/or the ability of our strategic partners and others to do the same.

### Information You Disseminated to Others

Certain UD websites offer features that allow you to disseminate or otherwise make available your personally identifiable information to others. These features may include, but not be limited to: posting a personal profile of yourself for others; uploading personal work and then making that work available to others; or participating in specific activities related to coursework, advisement, community building, and related endeavors that are reviewed by others. You will always be aware when you are disseminating your personally identifiable information to others, as you will be entering and submitting that information through an online form and/or similar method. Also, these features will often include additional information notifying you of the extent to which any personally identifiable information will be disseminated to others.

## Security

To protect the loss, misuse, theft, or otherwise unauthorized accesses of personally identifiable information, as well as the overall integrity of all information and services offered, our websites and associated systems maintain stringent security measures.

We take technical, contractual, administrative, and physical security steps to protect personally identifiable information and associated systems. In certain instances, such as when logging-in and/or when you provide credit card information in the purchasing of products or services, Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology may be further employed to protect your personally identifiable information.

Although we take appropriate measures to protect personally identifiable information, we can not guarantee that this information will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this policy.

## Updates

### Third Parties' Privacy Policies

Some services offered by the University have additional provisions.

 _Third Party Policy: SMS Messaging_ **  
** User information will only be used for the service they have explicitly opted-in for and will not be used for other services provided on this short code. User information will not be sold to a third party. User requests will not be used as a blanket opt-in to receive additional messages outside the context of the specific program they are opting in to.

### Links to Other Policies

Some of our websites may contain links to other websites not covered under this privacy policy. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such websites.

### Policy Updates

The University of Dayton reserves the right to make changes to this policy at any time.

### Contact

University Marketing  
University of Dayton  
300 College Park  
Dayton, OH 45469-1323
